In the discussion on responsive design,
在响应式设计的讨论中
I had briefly alluded to the grid system and the fact that many for
我们提到过网格系统
intent UI frameworks support some form of a grid system.
我说过 许多前端 UI 框架都支持 一定形式的网格系统
Bootstrap, in particular, supports the bootstrap grid system.
而 Bootstrap 支持的网格系统 就叫 Bootstrap 网格系统
In this lecture we are going to examine the Bootstrap grid
在这节课里 我们将详细地 学习 Bootstrap 网格系统
system in more detail and understand how we can leverage
并了解如何应用 Bootstrap 网格系统
a Bootstrap grid system to design responsive bootstraps.
来设计响应式网站
When we configured our web project to use bootstrap,
当我们配置网页项目以使用 Bootstrap 时
one of the first set of statements that we included in our
首先需要加入 HTML 的是设置了
html page was the meta tag with the viewport.
name="viewport" 的 meta 标签
The viewport enables our webpage to be able to identify the width of the device,
这个标签将使我们的网页 能够识别设备的宽度
and then appropriately adapt itself to the width of that device.
从而能让我们的网页 进行相应的调整以适应设备
So using this meta tag that we have here,
在这个栗子里 我还设置了 content="width=device-width"
we have specified that the width should be equal to the device-width.
这意味着我将我们的页面宽度 设置为了和移动设备的宽度一样
So essentially, we are occupying the entire device width as a return by
也就是说无论我们用什么移动设备 来浏览我们的网页
our device from which we are accessing this webpage.
我们的网页都能占据那个 移动设备的整个屏幕
So if you're accessing the webpage from a mobile phone or
比如 如果通过手机或平板电脑 访问我们的页面的话
from a tablet the device would match the screen width of our device.
我们的页面将会相应地占据 我们所用的手机或平板的屏幕
For laptops and desktops, we know that our browsers
对于笔记本和台式电脑 由于浏览器的窗口
can be any size smaller than the entire screen size.
可以调整得任意小
So our browser window can be smaller than the actual screen size of the device.
所以浏览器的窗口可以小于 任一移动设备的尺寸
So in those circumstances the device will be set equal to the width
此时 device-width 这项属性将会设置成
of the browser window that is being used to access our website.
当前浏览器窗口的宽度
So the viewport meta tag is used to be able to identify and set the device-width,
所以设置了 viewport 的 meta 标签 可以用于识别和设置 device-width
so that the content is appropriately rendered with this width in mind.
从而能使我们网页的内容以 正确的宽度来渲染
Designing websites to be responsive to the size of the viewport,
而若想设计对 viewport【视口】 尺寸响应的网站
requires us to use the grid system.
我们就需要使用网格系统
In particular in this case, the Bootstrap grid system.
而对我们来说 要用的就是 Bootstrap 网格系统
We will examine this in more detail next.
我们接下来会进行更详细的介绍
The Bootstrap grid itself is designed to be responsive,
Bootstrap 网格系统本身就是一套
mobile first, and fluid.
响应式的 移动设备优先的 流式栅格系统
So these attributes help
这些特性使我们能够
us to design responsive websites using the Bootstrap grid system.
使用 Bootstrap 网格系统来 设计响应式网站
We will examine how we go about doing this in the next few slides.
我们马上就会学习如何使用它
And then following that we will have an exercise where we will examine this
然后在那之后
practically in more detail.
我们会用一个练习以 对之进行更详细地学习
We have already seen the container class in Bootstrap in
在之前的练习和讨论中
the previous exercise and the discussion where we introduced Bootstrap to you.
我们已经了解了 Bootstrap 中的 container 这个东西了
The container class is used to enclose the content of our webpage.
container 类用来封装网页中的内容
So the container class enables us to define the width that our content is going
它让我们能够定义屏幕渲染时
to occupy on our webpage, when it is rendered in on the screen,
内容在网页中所占的宽度
so once you specify the container class depending on the screen size.
总之 当你定义好这个 meta 后
It'll automatically fix itself to an appropriate size to match the screen
你的 container 就能够基于屏幕大小
size or the browser window size through which you are accessing your website.
来调整它自己的大小了
Inside the container, we saw that we would divide our content into multiple rows.
然后在 container 里面 会分成若干的 row
Rows themselves are going to occupy the entire width of the container.
row 这个东西会占满整个 container
So the row will span the entire width of the container in this case,
如图所示
as shown in the picture here.
然后在每个 row 里面
Inside each row, Bootstrap divides the row into 12 equal sized columns.
又会有 12 个等分的 col
So this is where the Bootstrap grid system structure comes into place.
而这就是 Bootstrap 的网格系统了
So when you divide your row into 12 equal columns then,
当你把东西放在这个网格系统中时 你可以让它占据一行 12 个 column 中的
you can take your content, and then lay it out
任意多个 column
to occupy any number of these columns within each row.
比如说
So for example, you could lay out one piece of content to occupy
你可以让一个东西
the first seven columns of this group.
占据这一行的前七个 column 也就是前七列
So to do that we will specify it as shown in the picture there.
如图所示则是占据了前五列
We will specify the class as col-sm-5.
我用了 class="col-sm-5"
I will explain the details of that subsequently.
这个类及同一系列类的具体用法 我会在后面进行详细说明
But for the moment you can see how we are able to specify a piece of content to
不过从直观上来说 那个 col 和 5 都是
occupy five columns.
比较好理解的
Then we could have another piece of content occupying the remaining seven
然后如果我想让另一个东西
columns in the strip.
占据剩下 7 列的时候
So this way,
我再用 class="col-sm-7" 即可
these two pieces of content are going to be laid out on the screen side by side.
做完这些后 你可以看到 这两个东西并排地靠在一起
Between these two pieces of content there will be a small white margin left,
不过它们之间还是 有一个小小的间隙
what we call as a gutter.
我们管那个叫 gutter
We look at how Bootstrap configures all these different parameters for
对于应用 Bootstrap 网格系统的细节
laying out the content.
我们接下来就会说明
Bootstrap itself supplies four different classes
首先要明确的是 Bootstrap 从总体上而言
to target four different groups of screen sizes.
有四个"类"特别重要 它们对应着四种不同的屏幕大小
Extra-small to target the extra-small screen sizes, typically mobile phones.
其一为 xs, 也就是 extra small【"超小"】 这一"类"通常用于手机
Small for smaller screen sizes,
其二为 sm, 也就是 small【"小"】
larger than mobile phones, but smaller than say, laptops.
它一般用于屏幕大小大概在 手机屏幕大小和笔记本电脑屏幕大小之间
So this would be the tablet category, there.
的那些设备上
Then we have medium, md, which typically targets the laptop scale devices.
其三为 md, 也就是 medium【"中等大小"】 一般就用于笔记本电脑的感觉
And then finally, we have large, which targets large screens,
其四为 lg, 也就是 large 了【"大"】 顾名思义 就是用在大屏幕上的
screens that are greater than 1200 pixels in width.
如果要定量的话 就是屏幕宽度 大于 1200 像素的屏幕
In addition, Bootstrap provides us with these column classes,
这四种"类"会和其它的类组合起来使用 使用的场合在刚刚进行了说明
col-sm- whatever number,
所以我猜你现在知道 col-sm-5 之类的 是什么意思了
col-xs-, and md- and lg-.
就是当屏幕大小处于 sm 时 这个东西将占领 5 个 column
Correspondingly, these targetting the extra small, small, medium, and
col-xs-*, col-md-*, col-lg-* 等等等等
large screen sizes.
都是同理的
Now, when you layout any piece of content, you can specify how many of those
其中 * 处要用一个小于 12 的数字代替 以表明这个东西在特定的屏幕大小下
12 columns within a row this piece of content is going to occupy.
将占据 12 列中的多少列
So, that is why, when you saw the example earlier,
比如如果我对同一个东西 同时设置了
you saw that I specified a .col-sm-5, meaning that for
col-xs-12 和 col-sm-5 的话
small screen sizes, this piece of content is gonna occupy five columns.
意味着在 xs 的屏幕大小下 这个东西将占据所有 12 列
Now, looking at the details of all these sizes, when you examine this,
而在 sm 的屏幕大小下 就只占据 5 列
in this table here, we can see that we have four groups of screen sizes.
这里有张表格可以让你了解到 这四个"类"的一些细节
Extra small for any screen that is less than 768 pixels.
其中 xs 代表着任何屏幕宽度小于 768 像素的屏幕
Small for screen sizes between 768 and 992 pixels.
sm 则是 768 ~ 992
Medium for greater than 992 but less than 1200 pixels.
md 为 992 ~ 1200
And larger screens would be greater than 1200 pixels.
lg 则代表着任何屏幕宽度 大于 1200 像素的屏幕
Correspondingly to four different categories of devices that each of these
显然 每一个屏幕都会归属到
are targeting.
这四个"类"中的一个
Now the grid behavior itself for extra small screens,
然后来看看 Grid behavior【"排列行为"】
everything is laid out in single stacked be one below the other.
在 xs 下 所有东西都是
All the rows, and within the rows you can lay out columns
竖着一直排下来的
appropriately for small to large screen sizes.
当然 每个 row 里面 column的行为 是不会改变的
It will start collapsed first, but as you target the larger screen sizes,
而从 sm 开始 有些在 xs 里面 被折叠的内容就会展开
these will be laid out appropriately as specified by you using the column classes.
你可以通过指定
The will work also.
合适的 column 类来定制这些内容
You can see that depending on the screen size,
container 在不同的屏幕大小下
the container will be appropriately fixed.
也有着不同的表现
So for small screen sizes,
在 sm 屏幕大小下 container 的宽度
it is 750 pixel, all the way up to large screen sizes, which is 1170 pixels,
将会一直是 750 像素 在 lg 屏幕 则将会一直是 1170 像素
out of the 1200 pixels a mode that the width of the screen is sized to be.
不要忘了 lg 是指屏幕宽度 不小于 1200 像素的屏幕
In addition, for any one of these screen categories
不过无论 container 的 实际宽度为多少
the rule is always divided into 12 equal columns.
其内部的每个 row 都是等分成 12 个 column 的
The gutter width, again, as I've said between two laid-out pieces of content
而对于 gutter, 也就是每个 row 中
there will be some whitespace left over, which we call as a gutter.
相邻两块内容之间的那个空隙
The gutters width will always be 30 pixels.
将总会是 30 像素
So if you lay out two pieces of content, the first one occupying five and
比如如果你现在在一个 row 里面 放了两块内容 A 和 B
the second one occupying seven columns between these two pieces of content
其中 A 占了 5 列而 B 占了 7列
there'll be 30 pixel gutter left over as white space.
那么在 A 和 B 之间就会有一个 30 像素大小的空隙
So that way on the screen you will see these two piece of content
这个空隙就叫 gutter 这样一来, A 和 B 两块内容就能
sufficiently separated from each other, and clearly laid out.
比较清晰地区分开彼此
The column width itself is calculated depending on the size of the screen.
对于 column 的宽度 则是基于 当前屏幕宽度计算得到的
So for example, for small screens, as you see the column,
比如说对于 sm 屏幕
each column will occupy 62 pixels, all the way up to larger
每一列会大概占 62 像素 而对于 lg 屏幕的话
screens where each column will occupy at least 97 pixels or above.
则会大概占 97 像素
When you lay out content on the screen, you can lay out content to be
而正如我提到过的 我们可以针对 不同的屏幕大小来
displayed on the screen in different ways, depending on the screen size.
定制不同的排列样式
In the example that is shown on the screen here,
现在我们展示的这个栗子里
you can see that for extra small screen sizes,
我们对两块内容 A 和 B 进行了一些设置 以使它们在 xs 大小下
I have laid out the two pieces of content to be stacked one on top of the other.
将会上下排列 同时在 sm 屏幕 或更大的屏幕下时 将会左右排列
This I am specifying by specifying the classes as
我是通过对 A 和 B 分别设置了
col-xs-12 for both the pieces of content.
class="col-xs-12" 以使它们在 xs 屏幕下能够上下排列
But for small to large screen sizes
而如果此时我想让它们在
I want this content to be laid out side by side within a single row.
sm 或更大的屏幕下
Now this is specified, as you see on the right hand side of the picture above,
像右边这张图这样左右排列的话
you can see that for the first one, I specified the columns sm-5, meaning that
只需再对 A 设置 col-sm-5
the first piece of content will occupy five columns, the left most five columns.
和对 B 设置 col-sm-7 即可
And the remaining piece of content will occupy seven columns.
其中 sm-5 意味着 A 将会在 sm 屏幕下占据 5 个 column
That's why column sm-7 the seven columns to the right
sm-7 则意味着 B 将会在 sm 屏幕下
of the first piece of content.
占据 7 个 column
So this way, these two pieces of content will be laid out side-by-side on
这样一来 在 sm 屏幕下 A 和 B 就会左右排列了
any screen sizes, small, medium, or large.
由于我们没有再设置 md 和 lg 的类
You may be wondering why I did not explicitly specify for medium and large.
所以在 md 和 lg 屏幕下 Bootstrap 将会沿用我们对
Bootstrap, by default, if you do not specify the layout for
sm 屏幕的设置
some of the categories, then the earlier one that is specified for
事实上对于 Bootstrap 的某些属性 如果没有显式设置大屏幕下的表现的话
the smaller screen size will be automatically applied for larger.
Bootstrap 会自动把你对小屏幕的设置 应用到那些大屏幕上
So in this case, when I say col-sm-5, which means that for nd and
在这个栗子里我对 A 设置了 col-sm-5 但没有设置 col-md 和 col-lg
lg also, it's the same specification that will hold,
那么 Bootstrap 就会根据我的 col-sm-5 帮我设置好 col-md-5 和 col-lg-5
meaning that the one piece of content will occupy five columns and
意味着只要在不小于 sm 的屏幕下 A 都会占据 5 个 column
the second one will occupy the remaining seven columns.
对 B 也是同理的
Now, this is the standard way, if you don't specify any further,
这是 Bootstrap 的内置功能
this is how the content will be laid out on the screen.
能让你免于重复做某些相同的设置
Bootstrap also provides us with an additional set of classes called pull and
Bootstrap 还提供了一个系列的类
push classes.
叫 pull 和 push
Using the pull and
应用 pull 和 push 类的话
push classes, you can override the standard behavior of the layout.
你就能把网页中的一些内容 "拉回来"或"推出去"了
So in this example, you can see that for
那么这里有一个栗子 你可以看到 A 和 B 两块内容
screen sizes extra small, we are laying out the content one on top of the other.
在 xs 屏幕下仍然是上下排列的
The red one on top of the green one.
A 在上 B 在下
But for small, medium, and large screen sizes, the green one will be laid out to
不过在 sm 或更大的屏幕下
the left side, and the red one will be laid out to the right side.
你可以看到 与之前不同的是 虽然它们仍是左右排列
This behavior is specified by using the push and pull classes.
但 B 跑到左边而 A 跑到右边了 这是因为应用了 push 和 pull
So as you can see for the red content,
你可以看到对于 A 而言 我为其额外设置了
I have specified the column sm-push-7,
col-sm-push-7
meaning that this piece of content will be pushed right by seven columns.
意味着 A 将会被"推出去" 7 列
So essentially, occupying the last five columns in that row.
也就是意味着 A 将会 占据这个 row 的后 5 个 column
The second piece of content I have specified it as column-sm-pull-7,
对于 B 我除了 col-sm-7 以外 还设置了 col-sm-pull-5
meaning that this piece of content will be pulled lesswards by 7 units.
意味着 B 将会被"拉回来" 5 列 也就是占据这个 row 的前 7 个 column
So this way you can easily customize how the content is
所以有了 push 和 pull 之后
going to be laid out on different screen sizes.
你就能更灵活地定制网页的样式了
In addition to Push and Pull, we also have yet
Bootstrap 还有一个很好的类
another Column class type, call this offset.
叫 offset
Using offset, we can specify that a piece of content should be
它允许你"空出"一定的 column 出来
offset to the right by a certain number of columns.
在这个栗子里 我对一块内容
In this example I'm specifying
设置了 col-sm-offset-1
that the piece of content should be offset by one column.
这意味着在 sm 或更大的屏幕下 这块内容将会在其前面
Meaning that this piece of content will be laid out starting at column
"空出" 1 个 column 出来
number 2 rather than column number 1.
也就是从第 2 个 column 开始排版 而不是从第 1 个
If you don't specify the offset by default,
如果你不设置 offset 的话
the content will be laid out starting from column number 1.
Bootstrap 会默认你从 第 1 个 column 开始排版
Now, the other piece of content will occupy the remaining seven
在这个栗子里如果你在后面 跟一个 col-sm-7 的话 那么 col-sm-7
columns in this row.
将会占据剩余的 7 个 column
One last piece of modification that we're gonna see is the use of nested columns.
接下来我们要看的是"嵌套"的使用
Now, when we laid out our content
也就是说 我们完全可以在 row 里面 再用一个 row
to occupy two different number of columns on the screen,
如图所示 我就在右边的 col-sm-7 里面
then inside any one of those pieces of content, I can again go and insert a row.
插入了一个 row 然后在这个 row 里面
When I do that inside the column, that particular row will span exactly
我又能类似地加进一些内容
the number of columns that the piece of content is supposed to span.
对这些内容我能通过 一些 col 的类来定制它们
So in this example I see that the right hand side content is
那么对这个栗子 让我来叙述一下 它的层次结构
supposed to suspend seven columns, so inside the first row,
首先是一个 container, 然后是一个 row 在这个 row 里面
it is occupying the rightmost seven columns in there.
我插入了两块内容 它们分别设置了 col-sm-5 和 sol-sm-7
Inside that piece of content, I have introduced another row.
然后在 col-sm-7 里面 我插入了另一个 row
When I introduce this row, Bootstrap again will give me 12 columns inside that row.
对于这个 row, Bootstrap 同样会
So meaning that this content that is inside this content that is occupying
在里面给我安排 12 个 column
the seven right-most columns, they can now again be subdivided into 7 equal columns.
这 12 个 column 是在原先的 7 个 column 的空间中进行等分的
And you can then specify content to occupy any number of those
然后你就可以
12 columns inside the row which is inside another piece of content which is
利用这 12 个等分的 column 来类似地对你网页中的内容
occupying a certain number of columns in an outer row.
进行恰当的排版了
So this kind of nesting gives us a lot of flexibility
这种嵌套的行为将能让你以
in laying out contents for screens of different screen sizes.
更灵活的方式来在不同的屏幕大小下 对网页的各种不同内容进行排版
So now we have seen how Bootstrap's grid system allows us
以上 我们学习了如何利用 Bootstrap 的网格系统
a lot of flexibility in laying out our screens and
在不同的屏幕大小下
specifying how the content should be laid out for different screen sizes.
对网页的各种内容 进行灵活的排版
So now we will move on to our next hands-on exercise,
所以接下来我们将会 进行一个练习
where we will start with the exercise that we worked on
在这个练习里 我们会
in the previous set of lessons, and we'll continue modifying that webpage,
利用 Bootstrap 的网格系统
applying Bootstrap's column classes
来修改我们的网页
to properly layout the contents in that
从而使其能更好地 展示我们网页的内容
page in addition, we will also look at how we can introduce
特别的 我们还将学习如何 通过我们自己写的 CSS 代码
our own custom CSS classes into the webpage.
来定制我们的网页 【翻译 - Carefree0910】